William E. L. Bunn
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
William E. L. Bunn papers
1863-2009
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Bunn, William E. L.
12.8 linear feet
The papers of painter, muralist, and designer William E. L. Bunn measure 12.8 linear feet and date from 1863-2009. The collection documents Bunn's career as a painter, industrial designer, and his work on Treasury Department post office mural commissions through biographical material, scattered correspondence, project files, industrial design records, diaries and journals, writings and notes, printed material, photographs, and artwork. Also found are Bunn's papers regarding Grant Wood.
Provenance
The collection was donated by William E. L. Bunn in 1989 and in 2010 by Bunn's daughter, Chari Petrowski. In 1986 two sketchbooks and sketches were transferred with Bunn's permssion from the General Services Administration, which had received them from Bunn.
Alternative Forms Available
Two sketchbooks (Sketchbook #4 and Sketchbook #5) in this collection are available on 35 mm microfilm reel 3813 at Archives of American Art offices, and through interlibrary loan.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate copy requires advance notice.
Biographical Note
William E. L. Bunn (1910-2009) was a designer, muralist, and painter in Ft. Madison, Iowa and Ojai, California. Bunn was born in Muscatine, Iowa and received his B.A. in Graphic and Plastic Arts and an M.A. in Theater Design, both from the University of Iowa. In 1937 he was awarded a one-year post-graduate fellowship as an art intern for Grant Wood. From 1938 to 1942 he won four commissions from the Treasury Department to produce murals for Federal buildings. He also exhibited paintings, primarily depicting Mississippi River steamboats, at the National Academy of Design, Art Institute of Chicago, Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, and other group shows. Beginning in 1943 Bunn worked as an industrial designer at several companies including Sheaffer Pen Company (1946-1967) and Cuckler Steele Span Company (1967-1977). After his retirement, he and his wife, Annavene, moved to California, and he continued to paint. Bunn was also active in the Theosophical Society and had an interest in aviation.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of painter, muralist, and designer William E. L. Bunn measure 12.8 linear feet and date from 1863-2009. The collection documents Bunn's career as a painter, industrial designer, and his work on Treasury Department post office mural commissions through biographical material, scattered correspondence, project files, industrial design records, diaries and journals, writings and notes, printed material, photographs, and artwork. Also found are Bunn's papers regarding Grant Wood.
Biographical material consists of certificates, school records, Bunn family genealogy records, an interview transcript, and an autobiographical file maintained by Bunn containing professional summaries, lists of works, and other records. Correspondence documents exhibitions, awards, mural projects, and other commissions. Of note is correspondence with the General Services Administration, friend and fellow artist Lee Allen, and illustrated envelopes Bunn sent to his wife Annavene.
Project files contain photographs, notes, sketches, correspondence, and news clippings. Included is Bunn's notebook "Index to Projects" which provides additional information. Industrial design records include drawings and blueprints, employment records, photographs and publications, primarily from his work at Sheaffer Pen Company and Cuckler Steele Span Company.
Bunn's papers relating to Grant Wood include documentation from the Grant Wood Art Festival, as well as printed material, notes, and correspondence about Wood. Also found are photographs, including two photographs of Wood and photographs of his residence in Iowa City. Forty-one diaries and journals date from 1929-1951 and 1969-2003. Early diaries document art projects and school activities while he was a student at University of Iowa. Later journals document his work, travel, expenditures, and goals. Writings and notes include to-do lists, documentation on people Bunn knew, his artworks, lists of personal belongings, and topics of interest, such as astrology and steamboats. Also found are five notebooks on various subjects.
Printed material consists of exhibition catalogs, magazines, news clippings, and Treasury Department bulletins. Also found are announcements of mural competitions, postcards, and published images of steamboats. Photographs depict Bunn, his family, friends, and artwork. Additional photographs depict various subjects that were of interest to Bunn, including nature scenes, steamboats, airplanes, and bridges.
Artwork includes costume and theater designs created as part of William Bunn's thesis at University of Iowa. Also included are drawings and watercolors for potential art projects, as well as preliminary drawings and studies or technical drawings from his work as an industrial designer. Additionally, there are four sketchbooks, two of which include sketches and notes for the post office murals in Minden, Nebraska, and Hamburg, Iowa.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 10 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1910-2009 (Box 1, 12; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1927-2006 (Box 1; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 3: Project Files, circa 1925-2002 (Box 1-3, 12, OV 15-19, RD 31; 2.2 linear feet)
Series 4: Industrial Design Records, circa 1944-1977 (Box 3, 12, OV 20; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 5: Papers Relating to Grant Wood, 1935-2006 (Box 3-4, 12; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 6: Diaries and Journals, 1929-2003 (Box 4-6; 2.2 linear feet)
Series 7: Writings and Notes, circa 1928-2004 (Box 6-7; 1.0 linear foot)
Series 8: Printed Material, 1896-2009 (Box 7-8, 12, OV 21; 1.4 linear feet)
Series 9: Photographs, 1863-1990s (Box 8-9, 13; 1.6 linear feet)
Series 10: Artwork, circa 1926-2004 (Box 9-11, 14, OVs 22-30, RD 32; 2.3 linear feet)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Wood, Grant, 1891-1942; United States.--Dept. of the Treasury.--Section of Painting and Sculpture; United States.--Dept. of the Treasury.--Section of Fine Arts; W.A. Sheaffer Pen Company
Subjects-Topical:
Designers--Iowa; Federal aid to the arts; Muralists--Iowa; Mural painting and decoration--Middle West; New Deal, 1933-1939
Types of Materials:
Blueprints; Designs; Diaries; Drawings; Interviews; Photographs; Sketchbooks; Sketches; Transcriptions; Watercolors
Names:
Allen, Lee, 1910-2006; United States.--General Services Administration
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1910-2009, Series 1:; (Box 1, 12; 0.6 linear feet)
  Biographical material includes awards, membership certificates, diplomas, and other school records, as well as records relating to an exhibition and donation of papers at the Smithsonian Institution. Also found are Bunn family genealogy records which consist of family trees, photographs of family members, letters, notes, and one film reel (8mm) of a family reunion. Additional material includes an interview transcript, plans and notes regarding various studio additions, and an autobiographical file maintained by Bunn including professional summaries, lists of works, and other records.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically.
  - Address Book, 1983-2000s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Application to Reside at Krotona Estate, 2003-2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Autobiographical File, 1941-1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Birth and Death Records, 1910, 1942, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Certificates, circa 1929-1930, (Oversized items housed in box 12) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Diploma, Muscatine High School, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Diploma, State University of Iowa, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Exhibition Artwork Labels, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Family Reunion, circa 1976, (1 film reel) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Financial Loan Records, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Genealogy, circa 1916-2002, (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 11-15)
  - High School Reunion Booklet, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Index of Personal Documents, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Interview of William Bunn by E. Bradford Burns, 1948-1954, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Marriage Certificate, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Masons Membership Records, 1951, 2000, (Oversized items housed in box 12) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Muscatine Public School Records, 1920-1929 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Print-outs of Internet Searches for "William Bunn," 2000-2006 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Report Cards for Ricki Bunn, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Shriner Certificate, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Social Security Information, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Smithsonian Related Documents, 1987-2003, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
  - Stock Certificates, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Studio Additions, circa 1983-1993, (Oversized items housed in box 12) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Oversize Certificates, circa 1929-1930, (Oversized items from box 1, folder 5) (Box 12)
  - Oversize Masons Membership Records, 1951, 2000, (Oversized items from box 1, folder 20) (Box 12)
  - Oversize Studio Additions Plans, circa 1983-1993, (Oversized items from box 1, folder 29) (Box 12)
- Correspondence, 1927-2006, Series 2:; (Box 1; 0.3 linear feet)
  Correspondence is between Bunn and his mother, friend and fellow artist Lee Allen, Muscatine Art Center, and Karel Yasko of the General Services Administration. General correspondence files include letters regarding exhibitions of Bunn's artwork, awards, mural projects, and other commissions. Also found are many illustrated envelopes which Bunn sent to his wife Annavene. A few of the envelopes contained letters, but the majority of the original letters are not included. Researchers should note that additional correspondence can be found within the project files in Series 3.
  - Letters and Illustrated Envelopes from William Bunn to Annavene Bunn, 1961-1988, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 30-32)
  - Letters to William Bunn from Mother, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence with Lee Allen, 1981-1996, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
  - Correspondence with Karel Yasko, 1973, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence with Muscatine Art Center, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - General Correspondence, 1927-2006, (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 38-42)
- Project Files, circa 1925-2002, Series 3:; (Box 1-3, 12, OV 15-19, RD 31; 2.2 linear feet)
  Project files document Bunn's work as a painter and muralist. Bunn created a notebook "Index to Projects" late in his career. Each project, including his post office mural projects, was assigned a number and has a one page description and photograph within the notebook. Also found is a corresponding file for each of the projects from the index. Files may include photographs, notes, and sketches. Files on the post office mural projects are extensive and may also include correspondence, news clippings, and related publications. Researchers should note that additional drawings for these projects may be found in Series 10: Artwork.
  Folders are arranged based on the arrangement from Bunn's "Index to Projects." Researchers may want to consult this notebook before using related files.
  - "Index of Projects" Notebook, circa 1988-2001 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Mississippi Dawn, circa 1940-1995, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 44-45)
  - Punch and Judy Puppets, circa 1988 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - American Venus, circa 1953-1998, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 47-48)
  - American Venus, circa 1953-1998, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Capital, circa 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Ottumwa Belle, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Pauline, circa 1957, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Rainbow Portrait (Treasure Hunters), circa 1957-1968, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - Summer Morning, 1926, 1950s, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Torso, circa 1937 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Approaching Storm, circa 1992 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - The Great Divide, circa 1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Wyoming Hill, circa 1948-1997 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Landing Packet, circa 1940s (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Anita and Her Friends, circa 1940s (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bend in River at Muscatine, circa 1925-1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - City of St. Paul, circa 1940 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - City of St. Louis, circa 2001 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Northern Belle, circa 1938 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Showboat Goldenrod, circa 1942 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - High Bridge at Muscatine, circa 1930s (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Passing River, circa 1939 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Steamboat with Barge, circa 1950s (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - St. Louis Post Office Mural Competition Entry, circa 1939, (Oversized items housed in OV 15) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Dubuque, Iowa Post Office Mural, 1929-1990s, (7 folders; oversized items housed in OV 16) (Box 2, Folder 24-30)
  - Minden, Nebraska Mural, circa 1937-2002, (8 folders; oversized items housed in OV 17) (Box 2, Folder 31-38)
  - Hamburg, Iowa Post Office Mural, 1939-1994, (5 folders; oversized items housed in OV 18) (Box 2, Folder 39-43)
  - Hickman, Kentucky Post Office Mural, circa 1939-1940, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 44-46)
  - Magnetic Sky Phenomena, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Sunburst and Reflection Phenomena, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Decatur, Illinois Post Office Mural Competition Entries, circa 1930s (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Fort Madison Illustrations, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Miniature Steamboat Annavene, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Wedding Dance, circa 1920s-1996, (Oversized items housed in box 12, RD 31) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Morning Meditation, circa 1980s (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Guardian Angel, circa 1951-1993, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Redwood Forest Meditation, circa 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Hazzard Portrait, circa 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Schneider Mural, circa 1980s (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Hanley Monument, 1961-1995, (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 8-11)
  - Beth Kensinger Brown Portrait, circa 1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Libbey Park at Ojai Art Center Bridge, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Notes on Post Office Murals, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Oak Grove Krishnamurti Projects, 1982-2002, (Oversized items housed in OV 19) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Product Development for Vehicle Safety Device, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Proposed Murals for Sheaffer Pen Company, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Puppet Tour, 1933-1948 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Oversize Wedding Dance Drawings, circa 1920s-1996, (Oversized items from box 3, folder 1) (Box 12)
  - St. Louis Post Office Mural Competition Entry, circa 1939, (Oversized items from box 3, folder 15) (Box OV 15)
  - Dubuque, Iowa Post Office Mural, 1929-1990s, (Oversized items from box 2, folder 30) (Box OV 16)
  - Minden, Nebraska Mural, circa 1937-2002, (Oversized items from box 2, folder 38) (Box OV 17)
  - Hamburg, Iowa Post Office Mural, 1939-1994, (Oversized items from box 2, folder 43) (Box OV 18)
  - Oak Grove Krishnamurti Projects, 1982-2002, (Oversized items from box 3, folder 15) (Box OV 19)
  - Oversize Wedding Dance Floor Drawings, circa 1920s-1996, (Oversized items from box 3, folder 1) (Box RD 31)
- Industrial Design Records, circa 1944-1977, Series 4:; (Box 3, 12, OV 20; 0.6 linear feet)
  Found here are records of William Bunn's employment as an industrial designer, primarily for Sheaffer Pen Company and Cuckler Steele Span Company. Included are drawings and blueprints for Bunn's designs, day planners, employment records, photographs, advertisements, and product catalogs.
  - Barnes & Reinecke "Slotties," circa 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Cuckler Steele Span Co. (Cuckler Building Systems) (Box 3)
    - Blueprints for Cuckler Home Studio, 1968, (Oversized items housed in OV 20) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Day Planner, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Day Planner, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Day Planner, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Day Planner, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Day Planner, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - General Records, circa 1971, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 26-27)
    - Photographs, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Sheaffer Pen Company (Box 3)
    - General Records, circa 1950-1967, (6 folders; oversized items housed in box 12) (Box 3, Folder 29-34)
    - Photographs of Sheaffer Pen Company, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Photographs of William Bunn at Sheaffer Pen Company, circa 1960 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Pen Case and Pens, circa 1960s (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Oversize Sheaffer Pen Company General Records, circa 1950-1967, (Oversized items from box 3, folder 33) (Box 12)
  - Oversize Blueprints for Cuckler Home Studio, 1968, (Oversized items from box 3, folder 20) (Box OV 20)
- Papers Relating to Grant Wood, 1935-2006, Series 5:; (Box 3-4, 12; 0.5 linear feet)
  William Bunn's papers relating to Grant Wood include memorabilia and photographs from the Grant Wood Art Festival, catalogs for exhibitions of Wood's artwork, and printed material about Wood. Correspondence is primarily between Bunn and others regarding Wood, but also includes a letter of recommendation written by Grant Wood for Bunn in 1942. Also found here are various notes, a VHS vidoecassette of an event, and photographs, including two photographs of Wood and photographs of his residence in Iowa City.
  - Correspondence, 1942-2006 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Grant Wood Art Festival, 1993-1997, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 39-40)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1935-1973 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1940-2002, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 42-43)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1940-2002, (Oversized items housed in box 12) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - News Clippings, 1930s-2002, (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
  - Notes, circa 1967-2004 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, circa 1930s-2002 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Reproductions of Artwork, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Gathering of Friends of Grant Wood," 1991, (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Oversize Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1940-2002, (Oversized items from box 4, folder 1) (Box 12)
- Diaries and Journals, 1929-2003, Series 6:; (Box 4-6; 2.2 linear feet)
  Found here are 41 pocket diaries and journals belonging to William Bunn and dating from 1929-1951 and 1969-2003. Pocket diaries document the period that Bunn was a student at the University of Iowa and include brief accounts of his art projects and school activities. Later journals include time management schedules created by Bunn detailing his work, travel, expenditures, and goals. Some journals include sketches and attached photographs and documents. Also found here are an expense journal and a journal belonging to Jane Hehmeyer.
  Diaries and journals are arranged chronologically.
  - Pocket Diary, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Pocket Diary, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Journal, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Pocket Diary, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Journal, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Pocket Diary, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Journal, "Schedule of Time," 1932-1936 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Journal, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Journal, "Another Notebook of Another Try," 1935 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Journal, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Journal, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Journal, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Journal, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Expense Journal, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Journal, 1939-1941 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Journal, 1942-1946, 1949-1951 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1946-1948 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1969-1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1976-1979, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Journal, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Journal, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Journal, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Journal, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Journal, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Journal, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Journal, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Journal, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Journal, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Journal, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Journal, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Journal, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Journal, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Journal, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Journal, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Journal, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Journal, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Journal of Jane Hahmeyer (née Cutler), 1938 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Writings and Notes, circa 1928-2004, Series 7:; (Box 6-7; 1.0 linear foot)
  Writings and notes include to-do lists, documentation on people Bunn knew, his artworks, lists of personal belongings, and topics of interest, such as astrology and steamboats. One note card file box contains notes arranged by subject. Also found are five notebooks, including three that Bunn kept while a student at the University of Iowa for notes on art projects and university life. Two later notebooks contain notes on various subjects. Other miscellaneous writings include draft letters and project ideas.
  - Notebook, State University of Iowa, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Notebook, "Ideas," 1930-1931 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Notebook, "The Ideal University," 1932 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Notebook, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, circa 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Notes on Astrology, circa 1931-1965, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 16-18)
  - Notes on Steamboats, circa 1940s, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
  - To-Do Lists, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Notes and Lists, circa 1935-2004, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 22-25)
  - Notecard File, circa 1940s-1990s (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Student Essay on Chemistry, circa 1928-1929 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Call Slips for Bibliography, circa 1930s (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Writings and Notes, circa 1961-1994 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Writings by Others, circa 1938-1990s (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Printed Material, 1896-2009, Series 8:; (Box 7-8, 12, OV 21; 1.4 linear feet)
  Printed material consists of exhibition announcements and catalogs, primarily for group exhibitions including works by Bunn, books, magazines and news clippings, and Treasury Department bulletins. Also found are announcements of mural competitions, Bunn's collection of postcards depicting river scenes and boats, as well as other published images of steamboats.
  - Book, Moon Sign Book, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Book, Three Frontiers, by Robert Claiborne Pitzer, Illustrations by William Bunn, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Book, Wall to Wall America: A Cultural History of Post Office Murals in the Great Depression, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Book, Untitled Masonic Book, 1896 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Bulletin, Section of Painting and Sculpture, Nos. 2-7, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Bulletin, Treasury Department Art Projects, Nos. 8-14, 1938, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
  - Bulletin, Section of Fine Arts, Nos. 19-20, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Bulletins, University of Iowa, 1933, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1936-1941, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 15-17)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1942-1949, 1983-1990, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Magazines, 1988, 1990, (Oversized items housed in box 12) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - News Clippings, circa 1929-2009, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
  - Poetry Excerpts, circa 1960s-2005 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Postcard Collection of River Life and Boats, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Posters, circa 1980s, (Oversized items housed in OV 21) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Printed Material regarding Steamboats, 1929-1993, (6 folders) (Box 8, Folder 9-14)
  - Publications regarding Mural Competitions, 1938-1940 (Box 8, Folder 15)